A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Mission and church education in Nigeria and the Gold Coast (Reports 013208), 1949 (Box 684, Reel R-9290)
  Missionaries -- Nigeria; Missionaries -- Gold Coast; West Africa Education
- Review of Miami 1980: A different kind of riot, August 9 (Reports 013209), 1981 (Box 684, Reel R-9290)
  Riots -- Florida -- Miami (Fla.)
- Municipal service contracting (Reports 013210), 1981 (Box 684-685, Reel R-9290)
  08150787
  Public contracts; Council on Municipal Performance
- More effective use of books in American relations with Asia and the Near East (Reports 013211), 1952 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Briefing on program to expand the availability of Western books in Asia.
  05300057
  Book industries and trade
- The native Hawaiian legal corporation, 1975 (Reports 013212), 1978 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  07750099
  Hawaiians -- Civil rights; Operations Narrative Report
- The Nebraska experimental program in the use of television and correspondence study, 1957 (Reports 013213), 1958 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  05800268
  Television in education -- Nebraska; TV-Correspondence Study Department
- Neighborhood arson prevention: An evaluation in five cities (Volume I: Aggregate findings) (Reports 013214-001), 1986 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  08300579
  Arson -- United States; Natural disasters -- United States; Fires -- Investigation -- United States; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty
- Neighborhood Arson prevention: An evaluation in five cities (Volume II: Case histories) (Reports 013214-002), 1986 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Arson -- United States
- Draft assessment (Reports 013215-001), 1986 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Cosmos Corporation
  Support to develop and launch a national arson prevention demo and to document the results.
  Neighborhood Arson Information Management Systems Evaluation: working paper no. 4
  Crime prevention -- United States; Neighborhood planning -- United States -- Case studies; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; COSMOS Corporation
- Development of microcomputer systems for crime prevention (Reports 013215-002), 1986 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Neighborhood Arson Information Management Systems Evaluation: working paper no. 2
  Arson -- United States -- Prevention; Crime prevention -- United States -- Data processing; Neighborhood planning -- United States -- Case studies; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; COSMOS Corporation
- Baseline conditions (Reports 013215-003), 1986 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Neighborhood Arson Information Management Systems Evaluation: working paper no. 1
  Neighborhood planning -- United States -- Case studies; Arson -- United States -- Prevention; Crime prevention -- United States; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; COSMOS Corporation
- Neighborhood based Arson control: a guide to citizen-initiated legal remedies (Reports 013216), 1983 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  08350235
  Study and conference on the situations appropriate for invoking civil legal remedies to prevent arson.
  Arson -- United States -- Prevention; Law enforcement -- United States; Crime prevention -- United States -- Citizen participation; Neighborhood planning -- United States; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; Battelle Memorial Institute
- European security and U S policy (Reports 013217), 1972 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Narrative report to Ford Foundation. --T.p.
  Security, International -- Europe; Ford Foundation. Europe and International Affairs
- National Affairs division proposed budget, Fiscal Year 1969 (Reports 013218), 1968 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Social planning -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation
- Fort worth civic opera association, Inc.: financial statements year ended June 30, 1976 with report of certified public accountants (Reports 013219-001) (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  08100559
  The Fort Worth Civic Opera Association
  To improve and stabilize the financial position.
  Opera companies -- United States -- Finance; Performing arts -- United States -- Finance; Arthur Young & Company; Ford Foundation. Education and Culture; The Fort Worth Civic Opera Association
- Fort worth civic opera association, Inc.: financial statements year ended June 30, 1977 with report of certified public accountants (Reports 013219-002) (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
- Fort worth civic opera association, Inc.: financial statements year ended June 30, 1978 with report of certified public accountants (Reports 013219-003) (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
- Fort worth civic opera association, Inc.: financial statements year ended June 30, 1979 with report of certified public accountants (Reports 013219-004) (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
- National educational television semi-annual report July-December 1968 (Reports 013220), 1969 (Box 685, Reel R-9290)
  Public television -- United States -- Finance; Educational television stations -- United States; Television in education -- United States; National Education Television; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting
- Native American Rights Fund, Fourth Annual Report (Reports 013221), 1975 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Rights and Social Justice;Rural Poverty and Resources
  07200032
  Native American Rights Fund, Inc.
  Indians of North America -- Civil rights; Native American Rights Fund
- The Foundation Center and the Council on Foundations (Reports 013222), 1970 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- History; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Finance; Foundation Center; Council on Foundations
- The Foundation's agriculture and rural development program in Bangladesh (Reports 013223), 1974 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Memo to George Zeidenstein, dated November 19, 1974.
  Rural development projects -- Bangladesh; Agricultural development projects -- Bangladesh; Rural development -- Bangladesh; Agriculture -- Research -- Bangladesh; Agricultural assistance -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The Foundation's Bangladesh programs in education and research (i.e. social science and humanities and arts) (Reports 013224), 1974 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Memo to George Zeidenstein, dated November 21, 1974.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Bangladesh; Education -- Research -- Bangladesh; Humanities -- Research -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Funding for the arts in Europe and America Novemer (Reports 013225), 1980 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Arts -- United States -- Finance; Arts -- Europe -- Finance; Government aid to the arts -- United States; Government aid to the arts -- Europe
- Gaining access to drinkable water in rural Kentucky (Reports 013226), 1986 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Analysis of small water systems in 21 southeastern counties. --T.p.
  Drinking water -- Kentucky; Water-supply -- Kentucky; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- Gaps in research on transnational enterprises (Reports 013227), 1977 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  National Affairs/Office of the Vice President
  International business enterprises -- Research; International business enterprises -- Political aspects; International economic integration -- Research; Industrial policy -- Research; Centre on Transnational Corporations (United Nations)
- A general guide to Lagos for newly arriving Ford Foundation personnel (Reports 013228), 1969 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Prepared for the Lagos Office of the Ford Foundation ... --T.p.
  Employment in foreign countries -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Ford Foundation
- General support grants since 1951 (Reports 013229), 1963 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Staff memo dated March 11, 1963.
- Graduate division of Mexico's national schools of agriculture at Chapingo (Reports 013230), 1978 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Mexico; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Mexico; Agriculture and state -- Mexico; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Graduate education in the social sciences: meeting with Professors Angangoo, de la Cruz, Bennagen, and Ronas, University of the Philippines (Reports 013231), 1977 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  "[Report from] the third in a series of reports of meetings with faculty of the Division of Social Sciences, and the College of Arts and Sciences, University of the Philippines." --p. [1].[…]File memo dated May 6, 1977.
  Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Philippines; Education (Graduate) -- Philippines; Universities and colleges -- Philippines -- Administration; Social sciences -- Research -- Philippines; Endowments -- Philippines -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- A guide to federal rule making (Reports 013232), 1987 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  08600393
  The Focus Project
  Public information pamphlets and public forums in the federal regulatory process.
  Federal government -- United States; Administrative procedure -- United States; Transparency in government; OMB Watch (Organization: U.S.); Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice; The Focus Project
- Guide to personal policies: local overseas staff (Reports 013233), 1972 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Personnel management; Ford Foundation
- Ford Hospital (Reports 013234), 1972 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Medical education -- United States; Medicine -- Study and teaching -- United States; Medical personnel -- Training of -- United States; Public health personnel -- Training of -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Henry Ford Hospital
- Homogeneity and heterogeneity in education: interaction between personal resources and the learning environment in the effect on scholastic achievement (Reports 013235), 1981 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Academic achievement -- Research; Education -- Research; Research Institute for Innovation in Education (Jerusalem); National Council of Jewish Women; Ford Foundation. Education and Culture
- ICDDRB (International Center for Diarrheal Disease Research) board meeting, 4-9 (Reports 013236), 1980 (Box 686, Reel R-9290)
  Memo to David Bell and Oscar Harkavy, dated February 27, 1980.
  Research institutes -- Bangladesh -- Administration; Public health -- Bangladesh; International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh
- Education of undocumented children in Texas: a status report (Reports 013237-001), 1979 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  07700055
  Intercultural Development Research Association (IDRA)
  Partial supplemental terminal support of research and technical assistance regarding Texas minority school finance problems.
  Illegal aliens -- Education -- Texas; Illegal aliens -- Education -- United States; Educational law and legislation -- Texas; Education -- Research -- Texas; Education -- Research -- United States; IDRA Intercultural Development Research Association
- Mandated statewide students competency testing in Texas: an interim analysis (Reports 013237-002), 1979 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Educational tests and measurements -- Texas; Educational tests and measurements -- United States; Educational law and legislation -- Texas; Education -- Research -- Texas; Education -- Research -- United States; Intercultural Development Research Association (Tex.); Ford Foundation. Foundation. Education and Research; Intercultural Development Research Association (IDRA)
- Distribution of undocumented pupils in Texas public schools: a first look (Reports 013237-003), 1981 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Illegal aliens -- Education -- Texas; Illegal aliens -- Education -- United States; Education -- Demographic aspects -- Texas; Education -- Demographic aspects -- United States; School enrollment -- Texas -- Statistics; School enrollment -- United States; Intercultural Development Research Association (Tex.); Ford Foundation. Education and Research; Intercultural Development Research Association (IDRA)
- A proposal to research and effect school finance and property reform in Texas (Reports 013238), 1979 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Tax reform -- Texas; Tax reform -- United States; Taxation -- Law and legislation -- Texas; Taxation -- Law and legislation -- United States; Ford Foundation. Education and Public Policy
- The impact on nutrition on neurologically handicapped child (Reports 013239), 1978 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  07550307
  Support for a study of possible relationship between nutrition and neurological handicaps in children.
  Human behavior -- Nutritional aspects; Neurophysiology -- Nutritional aspects; Nutrition -- Research; Children -- Health and hygiene; Ford Foundation. National Affairs; The Regents of the University of California, Berkeley
- Implementation of ETV educational television in a developing country: a case study of Ethiopia (Reports 013240), 1973 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  This report comprises an attachment to the ETV project report for the Ford Foundation. --T.p.
  Television in education -- Case studies; Television in education -- Ethiopia; Educational television stations -- Ethiopia; Mass media in education -- Ethiopia; Stanford University. School of Education; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting
- Improving dryland agriculture in the middle east and North Africa (Reports 013241), 1979 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Collection of essays on arid regions agriculture.
  Arid regions agriculture -- Africa, North; Arid regions agriculture -- Middle East; Agricultural innovations -- Africa, North; Agricultural innovations -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Research -- Africa, North; Agriculture -- Research -- Middle East; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Improving productivity in city agencies: summary of recommendations and conclusions (Reports 013242), 1975 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Report to the New York City productivity council. --Cover.
  Administrative agencies -- New York (N.Y.) -- Management; Public administration -- New York (N.Y.); Program Planners, inc.; Productivity Council Staff
- India trip (Reports 013243), 1977 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Memo to Craufurd D. Goodwin describing his experiences in India while he was there under an EIA grant to prepare a retrospective analysis of "The Inter-University Study of Labor", which was intended to determine the nature and scope of teaching and resear
  Labor -- India; Industrial relations -- India
- Food policy in Indonesia 1977. (Reports 013244) (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Correspondence on food policy and nutrition policy in Indonesia.
  Nutrition policy -- Indonesia; Food supply -- Indonesia; Food production -- Indonesia; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia
- Industrial dislocation and its implications for public policy (Reports 013245), 1983 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  "Paper ... prepared for the third Annual Policy Forum on Employability Development, 'Displaced Workers: Implications for Educational and Training Institutions,' held in Washington, D.C., September 13-14, 1983." --p. [1].
  08350426
  The Trustees of Boston College
  Partial support for a planning grant to establish a labor research center and to develop agenda, structure and financing strategy.
  Deindustrialization -- United States; Unemployment -- United States; Labor policy -- United States; Manpower policy -- United States; Ford Foundation. Urban Poverty; The Trustees of Boston College
- Industrial preparedness: a key factor in keeping the United States out of nuclear war (Reports 013246), 1984 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Compendium of five papers on U.S. National Security.
  08351045
  The Analytic Sciences Corporation
  Support for a study on the linkages between military strategy and industrial preparedness.
  Industrial mobilization -- United States; National security -- United States; Analytic Sciences Corporation; Ford Foundation. International Affairs; Analytic Sciences Corporation
- Informe sobre el primer seminario de rectores miembros del consejo inter-universitario (Reports 013247), 1967 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Education, Higher -- Peru; Higher education and state -- Peru; Consejo Interuniversitario Regional
- Colonos en armas: las revoluciones radicales en la Provincia de Santa Fé, 1893 (Reports 013248-001), 1977 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Serie naranja, Sociologia
  Peasant uprisings -- Argentina -- Santa Fe (Province) -- History; Agricultural colonies -- Argentina -- Santa Fe (Province) -- History; Land settlement -- Argentina -- Santa Fe (Province); Economic development -- Research -- Latin America; Torcuato Di Tella Institute
- Tendencias en la evolucion de los salarios reales en Argentina, 1880-1910: resltados preliminares (Reports 013248-002), 1975 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Documento de trabajo / Instituto Torcuato Di Tella, Centro de Investigaciones Economicas;74
  Wages -- Argentina -- Statistics; Economic development -- Argentina; Economic development -- Research -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America; Torcuato Di Tella Institute
- La curva de phllips y el conflicto entre el pleno empleoy l estabilidad deprecios en la economia Argentina, 1964-74 (Reports 013248-003), 1975 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Documento de trabajo / Instituto Torcuato Di Tella, Centro de Investigaciones Economicas;75
  Wage-price policy -- Argentina -- Mathematical models; Inflation (Finance) -- Argentina -- Mathematical models; Full employment policies -- Argentina -- Mathematical models; Prices -- Argentina -- Mathematical models; Economic development -- Research -- Latin; Ford Foundation. Latin America; Torcuato Di Tella Institute
- Conflictos entre los objectivos de politica economica de corto plazo de la economia Argentina (Reports 013248-004), 1977 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Documento de trabajo / Instituto Torcuato Di Tella, Centro de Investigaciones Economicas;77
  Economics -- Political aspects -- Argentina; Economic development -- Research -- Argentina; Economic development -- Research -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America; Torcuato Di Tella Institute
- Adam Smith y los mercantilistas (Reports 013248-005), 1977 (Box 687, Reel R-9290)
  Documento de trabajo / Instituto Torcuato Di Tella, Centro de Investigaciones Economicas;78
  Mercantile system; International trade; Balance of trade; Economic policy; Economic development -- Research -- Latin America; Smith, Adam, 1723-1790
- Foundation Programming in Eastern and Southern Africa, 1990-1997 (Reports 013249), 1998 (Box 688, Reel R-9290)
  Memo to Katharine Pearson, dated May 1, 1998.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report to Office of Social Development, the Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-001), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
  Report of office activity from December 15, 1975 to January 15, 1976.
  Community development -- Southern States; Community development -- United States; Community development corporations -- Southern States; Community development corporations -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; K. S. Sweet Associates
- Report to Office of Social Development, the Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-002), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
  Report of office activity from January 15, 1976 to February 15, 1976.
- Report to Office of Social Development, the Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-003), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
  Community development -- Southern States; Community development -- United States; Community development corporations -- Southern States; Community development corporations -- United States; K. S. Sweet Associates
- Report to the Office of Social Development, Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-004), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
  Community development -- United States; Community development corporations -- United States; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; K. S. Sweet Associates
- Report to Office of Social Development, Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-005), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
- Report to Office of Social Development, Ford Foundation (Reports 013250-006), 1976 (Box 688, Reel R-9290; R-9291)
- Report to the Ford Foundation and AID - Evaluation of ARED, Asociacion para la Reforma de la Ensenanza de Derecho (Colombia) (Reports 013251), 1972 (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  Law schools -- Colombia -- Administration; Law -- Study and teaching -- Colombia; Ford Foundation. Latin America
- Report principal universities in the Lima area to the Ford Foundation in Peru (Reports 013252), 1967 (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  Universities and colleges -- Peru -- Lima; Education, Higher -- Peru -- Lima; Higher education and state -- Peru; Ford Foundation. Field Office Lima; Ford Foundation. Latin America
- Land ownership patterns and their impacts on Appalachian communities: a survey of 80 counties (Reports 013253), 1981 (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  07800399
  Highlander Research And Education Center, Inc.
  Partial support for Appalachian public policy resources program.
  Land tenure -- Appalachian Region; Land tenure -- United States; Appalachian Land Ownership Task Force; Appalachian Regional Commission; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice; Highlander Research And Education Center, Inc.
- Language and development publication announcement material 1975. (Reports 013254) (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  Drafts and final versions of publication announcements and publication order forms.
  Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Developing countries; Educational publishing -- United States; International Division Education program development
- Latin American agriculture development and policies (Reports 013255), 1968 (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  International studies in economics, monograph no. 8
  Agriculture -- Latin America; Agriculture and state -- Latin America; Agricultural Development Council; Ford Foundation. Latin America
- Law and bilingual education: A manual for the community (Reports 013256), 1978 (Box 688, Reel R-9291)
  To underwrite costs of final meeting of national Puerto Rican task force on educational policy.
  Education, Bilingual -- Law and legislation -- United States; Language policy -- United States; Education and state -- United States; Ford Foundation. Education and Culture; Research Foundation of the City University of New York (CUNY)
- Law reform project (Reports 013257), 1982 (Box 689, Reel R-9291)
  Indians -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Indians -- Land tenure; Indians -- Services for -- United States; Human rights -- United States; Indian Law Resource Center; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance
- The kidney problem: an exercise in the clarification of policy goals (Reports 013258), 1977 (Box 689, Reel R-9291)
  Public Policy and Social Organization
  Kidneys -- Diseases; Medical policy -- United States; Medical care -- United States; Ford Foundation. Public Policy and Social Organization
- Trip report: Seoul, Korea, January 18-24, 1973 (Reports 013259) (Box 689, Reel R-9291)
  Memo to Eugene S. Staples, dated February 12, 1973.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Korea; Social scientists -- Korea; Technical assistance -- Korea; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- Japan (Reports 013260), 1972 (Box 689, Reel R-9291)
  Industrial relations -- Japan; Labor market -- Japan; Labor supply -- Japan; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- Japan historical development experience and the contemporary developing countries (Reports 013261), 1978 (Box 689, Reel R-9291)
  07500476
  International Development Center of Japan
  American and less developed countries' participation in a Japanese research project on Japan's economic development and relevance to developing countries.
  Economics -- Research -- Japan; Central planning -- Japan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Japan; Industrialization -- Japan; Kokusai Kaihatsu Sentā; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia; Kokusai Kaihatsu Sentā